Guide to the Merle Hoffman Papers, circa 1944-2012 and undated, bulk 1961-2000 RL.00557
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal Files Series, circa 1944-2001 and undated, bulk 1961-1999, 25 boxes
  - New York Pro-Choice Coalition Subseries, 1979-1999 and undated
    - General New York Pro-Choice Coalition Files, 1985-1999 and undated
      - circa 1985, Mission statement (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986, Correspondence (Box P14)
      - circa 1985-1986, Membership list (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986 and undated, Correspondence and meetings (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986 and undated, Rally (1986 Jan. 22) and related events (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986, Rally (1986 Jan. 22) - contributions (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986 and undated, Rally (1986 Jan. 22) - endorsements (Box P14)
      - 1985-1986, Information packet and rally planning (Box P14)
      - 1985-1987, Finances - receipts and contributions (Box P14)
      - 1986-1987, Rally (1987 Jan. 22) - endorsements (Box P14)
      - 1986-1999, Finances - bank account and ledger (Box P14)
      - 1987 June, Learning Alliance newsletter (Box P14)
      - 1987, Button sale for National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL) (Box P14)
      - 1987-1991 and undated, Correspondence (Box P14)
      - 1988, "The Battle to Defend Abortion Clinics" pamphlet (Box P15)
      - 1988 and undated, Pamphlet design and materials (Box P15)
      - 1988-1989 and undated, "Back Alley" press conference (1989 Jan. 10) (Box P15)
      - 1988-1990, Pamphlet revision (Box P15)
      - 1989, Donations and thanks letters (Box P15)
      - 1989, Mayoral candidate questionnaire, 3 folders (Box P15)
      - 1988 and undated, Rally (1988 Apr. 29) - endorsements (Box P15)
      - 1989, Rally (1989 Apr. 2) (Box P15)
      - 1989, Teen Speakout on Choice (Box P15)
      - 1989, Teen Speakout on Choice - information packet (Box P15)
      - 1989, Teen Speakout on Choice - public statements and speeches (Box P15)
      - 1989 and undated, "Some Points for Clinic Defense" (Box P15)
      - 1989-1990, Public statement on Yusuf Hawkins murder (Box P15)
      - 1991 May, Bishop Daily at Choices - planning notes (Box P15)
  - Calendars Subseries, 1981-1999
    Contains the appointment books and daily planners maintained by Hoffman and her personal assistants, and includes both personal and professional appointments. In some cases, there are two or three calendars for the same time period, with substantially different content. In these cases, Hoffman and her personal assistants may have maintained separate records of Hoffman's schedule. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1981 (Box P16)
    - 1982-1984 (Box P16)
    - 1984-1985 (Box P16)
    - 1986, 2 folders (Box P16)
    - 1987, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box P16)
    - 1987, 3 of 3 folders (Box P17)
    - 1988 (Box P17)
    - 1989, 2 folders (Box P17)
    - 1990, 2 folders (Box P17)
    - 1991, 1 of 2 folders (Box P17)
    - 1991, 2 of 2 folders (Box P18)
    - 1993, 2 folders (Box P18)
    - 1994, 2 folders (Box P18)
    - 1995, 2 folders (Box P18)
    - 1996, 4 folders (Box P19)
    - 1997, 2 folders (Box P19)
    - 1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box P19)
    - 1998, 2 of 2 folders (Box P20)
    - 1999, 2 folders (Box P20)
  - Phone Messages Subseries, 1987-1996
    Consists of phone message books with carbon copies of messages left for Hoffman by others. Many messages are related to her work at Choices. There are occasional messages for other Choices staff members. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1987 Dec.-1989 June (Box P20)
    - 1989 June-1990 Dec. (Box P21)
    - 1990 Dec.-1991 Nov. (Box P21)
    - 1991 Nov.-1992 Aug. (Box P21)
    - 1992 Aug.-1993 July (Box P22)
    - 1993 July-1994 Oct. (Box P22)
    - 1994 Oct.-1994 July (Box P22)
    - 1995 Mar.-1996 Apr. (Box P23)
  - Clippings Subseries, 1974-1997 and undated
    Hoffman's scrapbooks form the bulk of this subseries. The scrapbooks consist primarily of newspaper clippings, but also contain some correspondence, publications of pro-choice organizations, photocopied photographs, and other materials.
    - Abortion - Newsday and New York Post clippings, 1989 (Box P23)
    - Clippings, 1994-1997 (Box P23)
    - Media coverage of Merle Hoffman, 1977-1980 and undated (Box P23)
    - Political cartoons, 1988-1997 and undated (Box P23)
    - Scrapbook, 1974-1995 and undated, 7 folders (Box P23)
  - General Personal Files Subseries, circa 1944-1999 and undated
    Includes educational memorabilia, one early diary, legal papers, and biographical information, arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Awards, 1984-1985 and undated (Box P23)
    - Car matters, 1996-1997 (Box P23)
    - Chesler, Phyllis - 50th birthday party, 1990, 2 folders (Box P23)
    - Chesler, Phyllis - book party invitations, 1988 (Box P24)
    - Diary, 1960 (Box P24)
    - Finance - canceled checks, 1979 (Box P24)
    - Finance - check register, 1999 Mar.-Apr. (Box P24)
    - Gold, Martin - divorce, 1979 (Box P24)
    - Gold, Martin - will, 1995 (Box P24)
    - High school diploma, 1964 (Box P24)
    - Hoffman, Jack and Ruth, memorabilia, circa 1944-1957 (Box P24)
    - Home - Florida house fire, 1995 (Box P24)
    - Legal papers
      - Estate planning, 1984-1995 (Box P24)
      - Merle Hoffman v. Camille Sasscer, 1980-1981 (Box P24)
      - M. Shakespeare, Inc. certificate of incorporation, 1995 (Box P24)
      - Peter Duchin Orchestras v. Merle Hoffman, 1980 (Box P24)
      - Traffic violations, 1995-1999, 1-2 of 4 folders (Box P24)
    - Legal Papers (Box P25)
      - Traffic violations, 1995-1999, 3-4 of 4 folders (Box P25)
      - Will, 1995 (Box P25)
    - Passports, 1964-1994 (Box P25)
    - Queens College diploma, 1972 (Box P25)
    - Resumes and biographical sketches, circa 1978-circa 1992 (Box P25)
    - Summer camp student magazine, 1962 (Box P25)
    - Van Wyck Junior High diploma, 1961 (Box P25)
    - Van Wyck Junior High autograph book, 1961 (Box P25)
    - Wedding, 1979-1980 (Box P25)
  - Electronic Format Subseries, 1985-1995
    Contains some writings by Hoffman and Phyllis Chesler, correspondence, graphics, mailing lists, and animal rights materials. There are also disks containing mixed files belonging to two or more series (for instance, Choices and On the issues).
    - "Animals agenda media list" mailing list, 1988. Disk 030: "Disk 14A, Desk lists, duplicate disk," from box labeled "7/88 7A-14A", 3 files (Box P25)
    - Chesler, Phyllis, letter and article on Bosnian rape victims[?], in Serbo-Croatian, 1995. Disk 061: "Serbo-Croatian Translation NOT WP 6.0", 6 files (Box P25)
    - Choices and On the Issues marketing correspondence, Choices Chatter (one file), and other Choices correspondence, 1986-1988. Disk 048: "Disk #4, Public Relations Duplicate Disk", 27 files (Box P25)
    - Choices mailing list and "Animals agenda media list" mailing list, 1985-1989. Disk 032: "Disk 14A, lists, duplicate disk," from box labeled "7/88 7A-14A", 21 files (Box P25)
    - Dennis the Menace cartoon graphics, 1995. Disk 057: "Dennis Scans 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18", 18 files (Box P25)
    - Dennis the Menace cartoon graphics, 1995. Disk 055: "Dennis Scans[?] 19-31", 13 files (Box P25)
    - Historical timeline concerning Bosnia[?], in Serbo-Croatian, 1995. Disk 060: "Serbo-Croatian Translation NOT WP 6.0", 3 files (Box P25)
    - Hoffman, Merle, writings, and Choices forms and policies, 1986-1989. Disk 050: "Disk 5A Forms- A.Walshe Duplicate Disk", 66 files (Box P25)
    - New York Pro-Choice Coalition list and letter, Women's Studies programs mailing list, and other mailing lists, 1988-1989. Disk 020: "Disk 7A Duplicate Disk," from box labeled "7/88 7A-14A", 15 files (Box P25)
    - New York Pro-Choice Coalition materials, Choices Chatter (one file), and Merle Hoffman correspondence, 1986-1989. Disk 046: "Disk 2C MH Duplicate Disk", 93 files (Box P25)
    - One unidentified mailing list, 1989. Disk 021: "#7B Duplicate," from box labeled "7/88 7A-14A", 3 files (Box P25)
- Photographic Materials Series, 1946-1999 and undated, 5 boxes
  For preservation purposes, many photographs were separated from their series and placed into this series. It is divided into Choices, On the Issues, and Personal Files Subseries. Each subseries is arranged in a parallel manner to the series with the same title in this collection.
  - Choices Subseries, 1975-1999 and undated
    Contains visual documentation of Choices clinic procedures and day-to-day operations.
    - Subject Files, 1975-1999 and undated
      - Choices East (Box PH1)
        - Conferences and speeches, Moscow, 1992 and undated (Box PH1)
        - Presentation on clinic procedures, 1992 and undated, 2 folders (Box PH1)
        - Presentation on clinic procedures - complete slide set, 1992, 6 folders (Box PH1)
        - Russian operating rooms, 1992 (Box PH1)
        - "The Russia Team Scrapbook," photographs and correspondence, 1992 and undated (Box PH1)
        - Signing letter of intent at Hospital no. 53, 1994 (Box PH1)
        - Visit to Moscow, 1992 Oct., 2 folders (Box PH1)
        - Visit to Moscow - negatives, 1992 Oct. (Box PH1)
      - Choices anniversary celebration, circa 1978 (Box PH1)
      - Clinic scenes, 1986 (Box PH2)
      - Clinic scenes, undated, 2 folders (Box PH2)
      - Exam room photograph, mounted for printing, undated (Box PH2)
      - Female condoms, 1992 (Box PH2)
      - Gold, Martin, award ceremony at National Abortion Federation conference - Medical Students for Choice, 1999 (Box PH2)
      - Gold, Martin, portrait, circa 1984 (Box PH2)
      - Hassibi, Mahin, and Gerri Abelson at conference, undated (Box PH2)
      - Hoffman, Merle, at Choices, 1975 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Photo album, Choices staff in clinic and at party, undated (Box PH2)
    - Outreach Files, 1984-1980s and undated
      - Awards ceremony for Riker's Island outreach program, 1984 (Box PH2)
      - Hoffman, Merle, at first sex education lecture for Girl Scouts, 1980s (Box PH2)
      - Riker's Island outreach program, undated (Box PH2)
    - Security Files, 1988-1994 and undated
      - Anti-abortion protesters in front of Choices, 1990 June 9 (Box PH2)
      - Bishop Daily prayer vigil, 1990 June 9 (Box PH2)
      - Front entrances for various clinics [removed from Operation Rescue file], undated (Box PH2)
      - McLaughlan, Harvey, and Raymond Fitzgerald [removed from Operation Rescue file, 1988-1994], undated (Box PH2)
      - Patient harassment article - contact sheets, 1994 (Box PH2)
    - Marketing Files, 1984-1988 and undated
      - Hoffman, Merle, lecturing on birth control - mounted for printing, undated (Box PH2)
      - Photograph for Choices calendar, 1984, 1988, 2 folders (Box PH2)
    - Operations Files, 1991-1998
      - Facilities
        - Flood damage, 1993 (Box PH2)
        - Medical equipment [removed from Bridge Plaza move files], 1998 (Box PH2)
        - Property Management correspondence - documentation of complaints, 1995 (Box PH2)
        - Tres Construction, Inc. notebook - "A negatives," 1991 (Box PH2)
        - Tres Construction, Inc. notebook - "B negatives," 1991 (Box PH2)
  - On the Issues Subseries, 1962-1998 and undated
    Primarily consists of proofs, author portraits, and other materials used in the magazine's production. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Correspondence, 1996
      - Artwork submission [removed from Merle Hoffman correspondence], 1996 (Box PH2)
    - Article Files, 1992-1996 and undated
      - Atkins, Dawn and Mary, Fat Activism - photographs and negatives, 1995 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Atkins, Dawn and Mary, Fat Activism - photographs and slides, 1992 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Kean, Leslie, interview with Alan Clements on Aung San Suu Kyi - slide, 1996 (Box PH2)
      - South Africa, photographs from Carol Bower, 1994 (Box PH2)
    - Editorial Files, 1962-1996 and undated
      - Africa photographs, undated (Box PH2)
      - Artists' submissions, 1991 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Chesler, Phyllis, photographs of unidentified women's event [Vancouver?], 1992-1994 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Lasch, Pat, sculpture show - review and slides, 1993 and undated (Box PH2)
      - Madre, Inc., photographs of Haiti, 1994 (Box PH2)
      - Millett, Kate, sculpture show - slides, 1962-1996 (Box PH3)
      - Staff members, circa 1989 (Box PH3)
    - Marketing Files, 1990-1993 and undated
      - "Feminist Government in Exile" campaign 1993
        - Andrea Dworkin (Box PH3)
        - Bella Abzug (Box PH3)
        - Copies for Merle Hoffman (Box PH3)
        - Flo Kennedy (Box PH3)
        - John Stoltenberg (Box PH3)
        - Phyllis Chesler (Box PH3)
        - Sponsor blurbs and correspondence (Box PH3)
      - On the Issues display at convention, with Phyllis Chesler, Bella Abzug, Charlotte Bunch, and others, undated (Box PH3)
      - On the Issues display, Barcelona Feminist Book Fair, 1990 (Box PH3)
    - Production and Distribution Files, 1989-1998 and undated
      - Production by Issue: Summer 1991 issue, Elizabeth I cover art, 1989 and undated (Box PH3)
      - Artwork and advertisements, 1994-1996 and undated (Box PH3)
      - Artwork and advertisements [removed from 1994 and undated], undated (Box PH3)
      - "McDonagh piece," circa 1997 (Box PH3)
      - Mosley, Leigh, photographs and resume, 1995 (Box PH3)
      - Photographs and slides
        - 1994-1996 and undated, 2 folders (Box PH3)
        - 1995-1997 and undated (Box PH3)
        - Film and TV publicity, 1998 and undated (Box PH3)
        - Film publicity, 1995 and undated (Box PH3)
        - Portraits, 1993-1998 and undated (Box PH3)
    - Staff Files, circa 1995
      - DiFranco, Ani, publicity photographs [removed from Karen Rose files], circa 1995 (Box PH3)
  - Personal Files Subseries, 1946-1995 and undated
    Includes extensive photographs of pro-choice rallies and other political events attended by Hoffman during the 1980s. The subject of other photographs varies widely, ranging from formal portraits, to childhood snapshots, to her vacation at the feminist Camp Sister Spirit. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Writings and Speeches, 1970s-1986
      - Hoffman, Merle, and Bella Abzug on first "On the Issues" cable TV show, 1986 (Box PH3)
      - Hoffman, Merle on set of "On the Issues" cable TV show, 1980s (Box PH3)
      - Hoffman, Merle with Roseanne Scamardella for TV interview on breast self-exam, 1970s (Box PH3)
      - Illegal abortion [removed from Abortion debates files], circa 1982 (Box PH3)
    - Politics and Activism Files, 1970s-1995 and undated
      - Demonstration in Bryant Park in a snowstorm, undated (Box PH3)
      - Demonstration in Bryant Park in a snowstorm - mounted for printing, undated (Box PH3)
      - Fundraiser for Betty Lall - Choices staff members, 1984 Dec. 12 (Box PH3)
      - Fundraiser for Betty Lall with Hoffman, Gloria Steinem, Ronnie Eldridge, and others, 1984 Dec. 12 (Box PH4)
      - Gold, Martin, with Mayor Abraham Beame, 1970s (Box PH4)
      - Hoffman, Merle
        - With Bill Baird protesting Nancy Klein case, circa 1989 (Box PH4)
        - With Andrea Dworkin, and Congressman John Lewis in meeting, undated (Box PH4)
        - With Phyllis Chesler, and others at unidentified event, undated (Box PH4)
        - With Ruth Messinger, and Noreen Connell at rally, 1985 June 8 (Box PH4)
        - Speaking at rally at Democratic convention, 1992 (Box PH4)
        - With Al Gore and Nita Lowey, 1994 (Box PH4)
        - With Betty Lall, 1984 (Box PH4)
        - With Bill Baird at rally, 1985 June 8 (Box PH4)
        - With Geraldine Ferraro, 1984, 2 folders (Box PH4)
        - With Rebecca Walker, 1995 (Box PH4)
      - Kennedy, Flo, at Merle Hoffman's home, undated (Box PH4)
      - Mondale, Walter, campaigning with Betty Lall, Ruth Messinger, and Betty Friedan, 1984 (Box PH4)
      - National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL) rally, 1985 Jan. 22, 2 folders (Box PH4)
      - Pro-choice rally for Geraldine Ferraro, circa 1984 (Box PH4)
      - Rally, 1985 June 8 (Box PH4)
      - Roe v. Wade rally in Bryant Park - Choices staff, undated (Box PH4)
      - Unidentified events and rallies, 1984-1989 and undated (Box PH4)
      - United Nations Conference on Women (Beijing) - snapshots of Hillary Clinton, On the Issues staff, and others, 1995 (Box PH4)
    - New York Pro-Choice Coalition Files, 1986-1989
      - "Back Alley" press conference, 1989 Jan. 10 (Box PH4)
      - Hoffman, Merle, giving speech [removed from Hoffman resume materials], circa 1989 (Box PH4)
      - Hoffman, Merle, with David Dinkens, circa 1989 (Box PH4)
      - Mayoral candidate questionnaire - candidate portraits, 1989 (Box PH4)
      - Mayoral candidate ratings press conference - copy for On the Issues, 1989 (Box PH4)
      - Rally
        - 1988 Jan. 22 (Box PH4)
        - 1988 Apr. 29 (Box PH4)
        - 1989 (Box PH4)
        - St. Patrick's Cathedral, 1989 Apr. 2 (Box PH4)
        - Bella Abzug speech, 1988 Jan. 22 (Box PH4)
        - Group portrait, 1989 (Box PH4)
        - [removed from New York Pro-Choice Coalition pamphlet materials], 1988 (Box PH4)
        - With Bella Abzug - contact sheets, 1986 Jan. 22 (Box PH4)
      - Teen Speakout on Choice, 1989 (Box PH4)
    - General Personal Files, 1946-1994 and undated
      - Camp Sister Spirit, Ovett, MS, with Phyllis Chesler, 1994, 1 of 2 folders (Box PH4)
      - Camp Sister Spirit, Ovett, MS, with Phyllis Chesler, 1994, 2 of 2 folders (Box PH5)
      - Childhood photographs, 1946-1962 and undated (Box PH5)
      - Childhood portrait, 1954 (Box PH5)
      - Crossing to England on the Queen Elizabeth II, circa 1968 (Box PH5)
      - Gold, Martin, birthday celebration, undated (Box PH5)
      - Hoffman, Merle
        - Portrait, 1985 (Box PH5)
        - Portraits, circa 1979 (Box PH5)
        - Portraits, undated (Box PH5)
        - Portraits as concert pianist, circa 1960s (Box PH5)
        - Portraits - glamour shots, undated (Box PH5)
        - Portraits - Polaroid, 1982 and undated (Box PH5)
        - Portraits, "(You Oughta Be) in Pictures," undated (Box PH5)
        - With Camille Barbone, Morocco, 1980s (Box PH5)
        - With her horses, undated (Box PH5)
        - With Martin Gold, undated (Box PH5)
        - With Martin Gold at unidentified events, undated (Box PH5)
        - With Ruth Hoffman and Bess Myerson, undated (Box PH5)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box PH5)
      - Van Wyck Junior High class photograph, 1961 (Box PH5)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1974-1998 and undated, 4 boxes
  Consists of audio recordings of radio talk shows on which Merle Hoffman was interviewed or was a guest, and videotape recordings of television shows and documentaries. Material is separated into audio and video recordings, and arranged by recording format within each category. Within each format, recordings are organized chronologically. The original title of each item has been preserved as far as possible. If running time is known, it is included in the item's description.
  [Originals closed to use. Some use copies available in the collection. Otherwise, Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
  - Audio Recordings, 1974-1997 and undated
    Chiefly recordings on cassette tape of radio talk shows featuring Merle Hoffman, with most dating from the 1970s or early 1980s. In some cases, these recordings feature Hoffman responding to listeners in call-in discussions of abortion, or conducting debates with anti-abortion representatives. Other audio recordings include interviews conducted for On the Issues stories and radio advertisements for Choices. Topics include contraception, managed health care, abortion, rape, women in prison, breast diseases, feminism, anti-abortion violence, and domestic violence. Hoffman's original title for each audiocassette is given in quotation marks, followed by a brief description of the cassette. There is one open reel audiotape. Arranged chronologically.
    - Audiocassettes, 1974-1997 and undated, 62 tapes
      [Originals closed to use. No use copies are currently available. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
      - Originals OR1-62 (CLOSED TO USE) (Box PH5)
      - OR1. 1974 July 19, "Guest on WTFM 'Community Report'": interview on "patient power," WTFM radio (Box AV1)
      - OR2. 1975 Mar., "Fred Long Show": Interview on abortion (second half) (Box AV1)
      - OR3. Circa 1975, "Merle Hoffman WQXR Editorial": Editorial on abortion and morality [tape damaged], WQXR, "Point of View" (Box AV1)
      - OR4. 1976 Aug., "Judy Ronald Marty Merle": Merle Hoffman with friends (Box AV1)
      - OR5. 1979 Jan. 4, "MH and ET 01/04/79": Merle Hoffman as guest host of "Coping through the Day," speaking on "patient power" and interviewing E. Teeson [sp?] on breast cancer, WNYC radio (Box AV1)
      - OR6. 1979 Mar. 27, "The Doctors": Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York meeting, speeches on state regulation of managed care (Box AV1)
      - OR7. 1979 July 19, "WMCA": Call-in discussion on contraception (second half), WMCA radio (Box AV1)
      - OR8. 1979 Aug. 6, "Coping Through the Day": Interview on mental health, WNYC radio (Box AV1)
      - OR9. 1979 Aug. 27, "STOP": Martin Gold, interview on STOP program for illness-related family problems, WNYC radio (Box AV1)
      - OR10. 1979 Nov. 27, "Merle Hoffman - Carl Weiss Show": Merle Hoffman as guest host of "Coping through the Day," on cancer (Box AV1)
      - OR11. 1980 June 8, "Equal Time": Interview on "patient power" with Merle Hoffman and Martin Gold, "Equal Time" show (Box AV1)
      - OR12. 1980, "G. Reilly [sp?] Hoffman Isaacs [sp?] 1980": Roundtable on feminism (Box AV1)
      - OR13. 1980-1981, "WQXR - Russian Roulette": Editorial on over-the-counter contraceptives, WQXR radio (side 1), and interview on "patient power," WRUD radio (side 2) (Box AV1)
      - OR14. 1981 Feb. 17, "Hoffman on HLA-OTC": Interview on Human Life Amendment, anti-abortion tactics, and over-the-counter contraceptives (Box AV1)
      - OR15-16. 1981 Mar. 15, "Debate Jean Head"/"M. Hoffman v. J. Head": Abortion debate with Jean Head, on Human Life Amendment, WXLO-FM radio, 2 cassettes (Box AV1)
      - OR17. 1981 Mar. 15, "M. Hoffman v. K. Quinn": Abortion debate with Kathy Quinn, WNBC, "The Family in Change" show (Box AV1)
      - OR18. 1981 May 3, "Ann Tripp WYTU": Interview on congressional anti-abortion legislation with Merle Hoffman and Betty LaRosa, WYTU radio (Box AV1)
      - OR19-20. 1981 June 5, "Ortiz/Richard Cavanavati [sp?]": Call-in discussion of abortion and anti-abortion congressional legislation, 2 cassettes (Box AV1)
      - OR21. 1981 June, "June 1981 Merle Hoffman": Interview on abortion and Hoffman's activism (Box AV1)
      - OR22. 1981 Oct. 11, "WYNY Radio Appearance": Call-in discussion of abortion and birth control with Merle Hoffman, Harriet Pilpel, and Lisa Desposito, WYNY radio (Box AV1)
      - OR23. 1981 Oct. 22, "The Home Show": Interview on breast disease [begins partway through Side 1], WEVD-FM radio, "The Jewish Home Show" (Box AV1)
      - OR24-25. 1981 Oct. 24, "Upfront (WOR News) Abortion": Abortion debate with Kathleen Quinn Vaccari, WOR News, 2 cassettes (Box AV1)
      - OR26. 1981 Dec. 9, "Merle Hoffman on Senior Edition": Interview on breast disease, unidentified radio station, "Senior Edition" show (Box AV1)
      - OR27-28. 1981, "Kathy Q Debate"/"Kathy Quinn": Abortion debate with Kathy Quinn, NBC [WNBC?], "The Family in Change" show, 2 cassettes (Box AV1)
      - OR29-30. 1981, "WBAI": Interview on Human Life Amendment with Merle Hoffman, Leslie Savanne [sp?], and Roz Cramer [sp?], WBAI, 2 cassettes (Box AV1)